Declan Greenhalgh

http://www.decln.com Email: dec@decln.com

Who I am

I am a software developer who works at Rightmove, in the Data Services Team, and have worked at ION Trading (in the FX space), and NatWest Markets (formerly RBS M&IB, within the Futures space). I have worked on both large-scale re-engineering projects, as well as smaller bespoke applications. Whilst I mainly work in Java 8, I am equally keen on working with .NET and Python technologies.

I have followed an atypical route into software development/management, having come from a psychology background prior to my computer science education. This background complements my skills in software engineering, with my main interests being in organisational capabilities, Agile practices and development processes - all contributing to regular delivery of high value change.

I aim to continue growing in an technical application management role, but still want to preserve my technical skills. Potential career paths that interest me include enterprise architecture and developer management, but in these early stages of my career I would like to get a variety of experiences.

Employment

Rightmove Plc.

Developer (October '18 - Present)

- > Full stack developer working on applications supporting property science.
- Working on Java versions 7, 8 and 11 developing Microservices
- > Front-end development in AngularJS and React
- Utilisation of Spring Frameworks (inc. Spring Boot)
- > Expanded testing knowledge using Cucumber and Selenium for front-end functional testing, and Pact for Consumer Driven Contracts

ION Trading Ltd

Developer (February '18 - September '18)

- Worked on a large-scale FX trade management re-engineering project.
- ➤ Primarily used Java 8.
- > Use of ATDD (Robot Framework) and mocking frameworks (Mockito).
- > Utilised dependency injection frameworks (Guice), and Spring Hibernate.
- > Focused on delivery of a post-trade solution with an emphasis on service-oriented architecture.
- > Gained experience working with larger Agile teams using the LeSS framework.

NatWest Markets (Royal Bank of Scotland Group)

Application Manager / Developer - Associate (September '17 - February '18)

- > A continuation of the below role, in a permanent capacity.
- > An increased focus on application design, project management, stakeholder management, and providing services as the application SME.
- > Worked on the implementation of various MiFID II project deliverables.

MThree Consulting Ltd / NatWest Markets

Developer (September '15 - September '17)

- > Worked primarily in an application management/developer role in the Futures Technology space.
- Day-to-day was working on the in-house Futures Execution & Clearing Order Management System that handles execution and allocation routing between the full F2B stack. Have previously worked on a major transformation project due to a 3rd-party vendor switch, working on the entire lifecycle in an agile environment.
- > Have been responsible for the implementation of CMMI within my application.
- > Technologies used include Java 7, FIX Protocol, Oracle SQL, Unix, TIBCO EMS, IBM MQ and a variety of agile tools.

University of Kent Information Services

Assistant Support Desk Supervisor (September 2014 – August 2015)

- > Role included supervisory & SME aspects.
- Required to manage the University IT services at the weekend and out of hours.

IT and Library Support Desk Assistant (April 2013 – September 2014)

- Customer-facing helpdesk role helping with technical issues.
- > Helped develop my abilities to deal with a range of customers, communicating with relevant colleagues and maintaining a presentable, professional work environment.

Education

MSc. Computer Science, University of Kent, 2014 - 2015

Obtained a Master's degree in a programme covering a wide range of computing concepts, including: Java-based Object Oriented Programming, Web-Based Information Systems, Logic Programming, Machine Learning and Systems Architecture.

BSc. (Hons.) Psychology and Sociology, University of Kent, 2011-2014

Obtained a 2:1. Undertook two research projects in my final year, including a technical-based electroencephalography study in Psychology.

Lancaster Royal Grammar School, 2005-2011

Obtained an 'A' grade in History, and 'B' grades in Chemistry, French, Drama and General Studies A-Levels. Gained 12 GCSEs A*-C, including English Literature (A*), English Language (A) and Maths (A).

Professional Affiliations:

- British Psychological Society, with a title of MBPsS. Part of the Division of Occupational Psychology.
- ➤ British Computing Society, with the title of AMBCS. Member of additional Specialist Groups including Software Process Improvement Network, Software Practice Advancement, Agile Methods, Financial Services and Advanced Programming.

Additional Information & Interests

- I enjoy playing the piano in my spare time.
- > Treasurer and committee member of the University's trampolining team for two years.
- British Gymnastics' qualified judge, and have judged at national competitions to an elite level.
- Received Green Colours from Kent Sport for the administrative service I provided to the club.